mjobs.net 2014-09-04

# Ethio Mobile Job - Privacy Terms

**Privacy**

This website is managed and maintained by Somtec Trading PLC (Somtec). This privacy statement refers to the handling of personal information by Somtec.

Somtec may review and update this privacy statement. Revised versions will be available on the website.

**How Somtec uses your personal information**

Somtec collects personal information about you so you can take full advantage of MJobsethio.com services and to assist you to find employment. The relevant personal and protected information collected by Somtec includes, but is not limited to, your name, date of birth, gender, home phone, other phone, mobile phone, fax, email and personal website.

Your personal information is used to:

  * determine if you are eligible to register on mjobsethio.com 
  * give you employment opportunities
  * evaluate and monitor outcomes, programs and services delivered by Job Services Australia providers
  * assist in resolving complaints made by you or Employer
  * include you in surveys conducted by Somtec and its contracted providers
  * help in the administration of programs
  * help Somtec improve its service to job seekers.

By using Mjobsethio.com you consent to your personal information being used for the above purposes.

**Who has access to your personal information?**

Somtec may share job seekers’ personal and protected information with third parties to deliver its employment services and assist you to find employment.

By applying for a position advertised on Mjobsethio.com you are requesting and authorising that Somtec pass your personal information to the employer as a part of your application.

Job seekers’ personal information may be disclosed by Somtec to:

  * employment service providers - to assist them provide employment services
  * recruitment organisations 
  * employers.

When Somtec contracts third parties to assist in performing employment services, Somtec requires that all third parties comply with Somtec’s privacy policy.

Somtec may disclose job seekers’ personal information to third parties in certain limited circumstances. This includes:

  * to prevent or lessen a serious and imminent threat to the life or health of the individual concerned or another person
  * when disclosure is required or authorised by law; or for the enforcement of criminal law or of a law imposing a fine
  * for the protection of public revenue.

How your information is collected

**Personal information**

Somtec collects your personal information directly from you when you register or update your personal information on Mjobsethio.com. There are circumstances where personal information comes from a third party, if you have agreed or would reasonably expect your personal information to be collected in this way.

When you register your personal information on Mjobsethio.com, you will be asked to select what personal information you want to be displayed on your resume.

**Anonymous information about visitors**

When you visit Mjobsethio.com, Somtec records anonymous information about your visit and logs the following information for statistical purposes:

  * your server address
  * your top level domain name (for example, .com, .net, .com.et etc)
  * the date and time of visit to the site
  * the pages accessed and documents downloaded
  * the previous site visited
  * the type of browser used.

This information is not specific to you and is used for system administration purposes, as well as statistical analysis. While anonymous information does not tell us anything about you specifically, it tells us about how you use our site. 

**Cookies**

Somtec uses cookies and other technologies to enhance job seekers’ online experience and collect data about the use of Mjobsethio.com in order to improve the quality of service.

A cookie is a small text file that a server places on your hard drive to identify that subsequent requests to a site have come from the same user. Somtec uses cookies to ‘remember’ your browser between page visits. The cookie identifies your browser, not you personally. Somtec uses cookies on Mjobsethio.com to develop patterns of site usage. No personal information is stored within Mjobsethio.com cookies. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to deny or accept the cookie feature. For more information on cookies please refer to the help menu within your internet browser.

**Google Analytics**

Somtec uses Google Analytics to collect information about visitors to its website. Google Analytics uses first-party cookies and JavaScript code to help analyse how users use the site. It anonymously tracks how our visitors interact with this website, including how they have accessed the site (for example from a search engine, a link, an advertisement etc) and what they did on the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purposes of compiling reports on website activity and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser.

**Browsing activities**

Somtec only identifies users by their browsing activities in cases where a law enforcement agency exercises a warrant to inspect Somtec's logs, or for the purposes of market research conducted by Somtec or its contractors.

**Personal and Protected Information**

The personal and protected information Mjobsethio.com collects includes among others your name, address, gender. This information is handled by Somtec in accordance with national and local privacy and social security law.

**Email address / Phone number**

Somtec will record your email address and phone number to enable you to use the services provided by Mjobsethio.com. It will only be used for the purpose for which you have provided it. It maybe added on a mailing and contact list unless you specifically ask not to be added on that list.

**Protection of personal information**

Somtec takes all reasonable steps to ensure the security of its systems. We allow job seekers to access their personal information to keep it accurate and up to date. Any personal information which Somtec holds for job seekers is stored on secure servers that are protected in controlled facilities.

Mjobsethio.com, Somtec and the contractors who provide services related to our information systems are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held. However, Somtec will not be responsible for events arising from unauthorised access of job seekers’ personal information.

You can also play an important role in keeping your personal information secure, by maintaining the confidentiality of any username and password. Please notify us immediately if there is any unauthorised use of your account by any other internet user or any other breach of security.

Mjobsethio.com may contain links to external sites. Somtec is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these sites. You should note there are inherent risks associated with transmission of information via the internet. Therefore you should make your own assessment of the potential risks to the security of information when making a decision as to whether or not to use external sites that are linked to or from Mjobsethio.com.

**Please Note:**

Mjobsethio.com advises job seekers to protect their privacy by ensuring they do not provide personal information, including bank account details to anyone they do not know.  Job seekers are urged not to provide bank account details to any prospective employer until you have signed a contract of employment and/or you are satisfied with the bona fides of that employer. 

Your privacy concerns

If you have concerns about the way your personal information is being managed by Somtec, or Somtec contracted organisations, you should discuss your concerns with us.

How to contact us

If you have enquiries or wish to provide feedback about this policy, please email info@mjobsethio.com
